A Guide to the Ralph Hickman Davis papers, 1943-2014
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Ralph Hickman Davis papers, 1943-2014
The Library of Virginia
50284
.675 cu. ft., 2 boxes
Ralph Hickman Davis
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Clinton M. Davis of Staunton, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Ralph Hickman Davis was born 5 February 1915 in Providence, Rhode Island, to William and Rhoda Davis. He graduated from East Providence High School in 1934. Davis played baseball with some independent African American teams and with area teams, helping to desegregate the Piedmont Twilight League and the Pawtucket Inter City League. Davis also learned to fly, receiving his pilot's license in 1939, and he would eventually be inducted into the Rhode Island Aviation Hall of Fame. Davis enlisted in the Army Air Corps in November 1941 and was a pilot, instructor, and mechanic for the 99th Pursuit Squadron, the Tuskegee Airmen. Honorably discharged in 1945, Davis settled down with his wife Mary Tate Davis in her hometown of Staunton, Virginia, and they had one son. Davis continued his interest in flying and restored a Piper Cub J-3 airplane. Davis died in 2002.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1943-2014, of Ralph Hickman Davis (1915-2002) of Rhode Island and Staunton, Virginia, consisting of articles, booklets, brochures, military records, photographs, scrapbooks, yearbooks, and other materials detailing Davis's service with the 99th Pursuit Squadron--the Tuskegee Airmen--during World War II (Tuskegee yearbook is on CD); his post-war activities in aviation; and his pre-World War II baseball activities. Collection contains articles, judicial records, photographs, receipts and other papers concerning Mary Tate Davis (1920-1983), the Davis family of Rhode Island, and the Tate family of Staunton. Collection also includes CDs containing photographs of the Davis and Tate families--many of the photographs are in the collection as hard copies. Papers also include information on the Brown Colbert (1785-1833) family and the Edmondson family of West Virginia.
Contents List
- Ralph H. Davis military records, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Piper Cub J-3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ralph H. Davis general papers (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Rhode Island Aviation Hall of Fame, 21 November 2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ralph Davis commemoration by the Pawtucket Red Sox, 16 July 2012 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Ralph H. Davis baseball glove (photograph) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Ralph H. Davis and Mary Tate Davis photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mary Tate Davis (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Davis family papers (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Davis family photographs (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Davis family photographs (CD disc) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Ralph Davis and Clinton Davis--camping and Good Sam RV club (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Davis-Tate family photographs (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Tate family papers, 1885-1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Luther Tate and Lavinia Branson Tate photographs (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Tate-Branson family papers (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Tate-Branson family photographs (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Tate and related families funeral bulletins (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Brown Colbert family, also Thomas Jefferson and slavery exhibitions (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Brown and Edmondson families--Bill Webb correspondence (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Edmondson family papers (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Edmondson family papers: The Hemings Family's Civil War (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Tuskegee Airfield yearbook, ca. 1943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- 99th Pursuit Squadron, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Physical training department, Tuskegee Air Field, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- The Tuskegee Airmen (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Tuskegee Airmen--articles and clippings (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Tuskegee Airmen program--Staunton, Virginia, 15 July 2012 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Tuskegee Airmen National Historic Site (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Reunion of Tuskegee groundcrews--Rantoul, Illinois, Chanute Field (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Dr. Carter G. Woodson African American History Museum, St. Petersburg, Florida--Tuskegee Airmen exhibit (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Scrapbook--Tuskegee Air Field; St. Petersburg, Florida; Chanute Field, Rantoul, Illinois; Germany, ca. 1980s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Military planes photographs (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Photographs--Jamestown; Colonial Williamsburg; Marine Museum, Quantico, Virginia; World War II memorial, Washington DC; Edmund Pettus Bridge, Selma, Alabama; Alaska; aerial view of Staunton, Virginia (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Winchester rifle (Box 2, Folder 9)
- African American businesses in Staunton and Fairview Cemetery (Box 2, Folder 10)